welcome back uh so in this session we
are going to talk about some additional
topics and we are going to talk about
the t-box automation modules
now there are several automation modules
which are present in the standard subset
provided by Tosca and you can use them
for many General operations when you are
working with your test cases so these
are kind of a library which is available
to you and you don't need to write any
additional tests for performing all
these operations now we are going to
talk about some file operations folder
operations uh numeric operations and
some process operations which are
available in Tosca t-box automation
module
so uh let's get started uh first with
the file operations so for that I have
created a folder in my test cases t-box
modules
and in this um I'm going to create
another folder called file operations
okay so inside this we are going to see
many operations which you can perform on
different files using this dbox
automation modules okay so uh we'll
first start with image compare how you
can compare two images right so t-box
has provided a module for it and we can
use that so let's add a test case here
and we'll say it compare images
okay
and then I'm going to add a desktop
which is nothing but a module so I'm
going to search t-box image compare okay
so that's the module
and once you add them you will see uh
you just need to provide uh two things
here first image file path and second
image file path okay so either you can
browse it or you can directly copy paste
the path
so I'm going to browse the path I have a
folder where I have two images you can
see right both look different
so I'm going to compare these two images
using this particular module
okay so that's all we need to do here
and then I can directly go ahead and run
this in scratchbook
okay as expected uh the verification
field uh because the images were not
same right so that was the expected
result
and moving on to our next uh t-box
module uh and that is on how you can
create different files uh in a
particular folder using the t-box module
right so let's call it create files
okay
and then I'm going to add the test step
so let's search for t-box create
and that's the third one t-box read
create file so you can use the same
module to read or create new files okay
so let's select the directory
um I will use the same directory which I
have created
so
this one and then we have to give a file
name here okay so it is the name of the
file so I am calling it test1 dot txt
and what text do you require in this
particular file you can even create that
or you can write it to the text file
okay
so I will call it this is a test
right for creating
files
and then we have to provide uh encoding
so you can either provide utf-8 or
utf-16 okay
so let's go with utf-8 override I will
set it to true and add byte auto mark I
will set it to true
okay
so these are the values which you need
to provide when you are going ahead and
adding this particular module okay
um and let's go ahead and run this now
and once it is finished you will see uh
it has created a test one file in this
particular folder right scratchbook will
show the past result and as you can see
the folder where we have given the
location as
it has created a file with the text what
we have provided right so it's easy to
create any particular file using this
right
and let's go ahead and see what other
modules are present for uh the t-box
automation module for file operations
right
so the next automation module which I
can use is copy file right so now I have
created a file let's see how we can copy
file using this t-box module so again
um let me search for t-box copy file
okay and I can give a source and a
Target directory right so
let's take this as the source okay and
then let's
go ahead and let's copy this into some
other folder Okay so
let's go into C samples
and then uh I have to give a Target file
name okay so I'll call it test2 dot txt
and override I will set it to true
right
okay so let's go ahead and run this
right let's uh go ahead and check this
now I am in the C samples folder as you
can see and now I can see that a test 2
file has been created here okay
so that's how you can copy any
particular file not only txt files you
can also copy XML files right so any
files uh within your directories
and now uh let's see how we can compare
to particular files using our t-box
module right so this could be useful
whenever you are trying to compare files
right Force whether they have the same
content or not it's a very common
scenario in your test cases
so this could be uh very useful right so
let's see t-box compare file compare
okay similar to what we have for images
this is for files okay
so I need to give a
first file path and the second file path
okay so let's copy this particular file
and create a new file here right so that
we can test it
and let's go ahead with the same content
here
and let's rename this file to test two
okay
so let's compare these two files now
test one and
test two
and we will keep this as the same folder
so C
and training okay
so let's go ahead and run this now
right uh so in the log info you can see
it is showing that contents of the file
are identical right so we can also go
here
okay so as you notice uh there is no
report file generated because put the
content are same right so let's go ahead
and change uh something in our test1
file
right and save it
okay so let's go ahead and run this
again and this time around we should see
some reports saying that it's not
matching and what's the difference okay
obviously the test case will fail
because the verification has failed okay
but let's go ahead and check the report
so you can see uh it's a HTML report
and uh it will show you uh something
highlighted in red that this is what is
not matching okay
so this is the additional content
and or this is the missing content in
the second file okay so it is showing in
red
so that's the kind of report uh you can
get if you're comparing two files okay
so our final test automation module in
this file operations is how to delete a
file
so let's uh rename this test case to
delete file and let's go ahead and add
the test step
so search for t-box delete file
and let's select the folder here
okay so let's give it a file name here
and it should be test one dot txt
that's the file I want to delete so
let's go ahead and run this
and that particular file should not be
present here now okay
so that's how you can delete files uh
and
that's how you can use different t-box
modules in order to perform different
file operations like comparing images
comparing files creating files copying
files deleting files there's also some
other t-box modules which you can
um try for on your own which are like
you can read the files as I showed you
you can also move rename and you can
also append uh to a particular file okay